Guide to the Center for International Studies records, 1960-1983.
Center for International Studies records
- Series VI. CIS Committees and Affairs
  - Summary of the Preliminary Recommendations of the CIS Evaluation Committee, March 27, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Assorted CIS Planning Committee Documents, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Internationa1 Studies at Cornell University: Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Assorted Papers on CIS Programs and Causes, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - History and Goals of CIS Undergraduate Interdisciplinary Program (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Undergraduate Interdisciplinary Program in International Studies, Proposals and Assorted Documents, Early 1970s (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Assorted Documents for CIS Undergraduate Involvement, Early 1970s (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence Focusing Upon Annual International Development Conference, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Outline for UCLA's International Development Seminar and Waking Papers Description by John Lindeman, April 1965 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Assorted International Development Papers, May 1966 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - "Questionnaire for International Development at Cornell University" (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Assorted International Development Notes (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Modernization Workshop, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - MW Administrative, 1962-1966 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - "Modernization Workshop: Rough Notes on Distribution, Productivity and Roundaboutness with Some Reference to Modernization", October 8, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - MW Administration, 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Executive Committee Reorganization, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Executive Committee Meetings, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Executive Com. Membership Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - CIS Executive Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Luncheons and Meetings (Only Record of Committee Memberships for Period before 1972), Before 1972 (Box 15)
  - Executive Committee Meetings prior to 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Executive Committee Meetings, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Executive Committee Meetings, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Executive Committee Meetings, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Executive Committee Meetings, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - "International Studies at Cornell University: Annual Report", 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Revised Proposal - "An Evaluation of Undergraduate, Problem Orientated, Interdisciplinary Courses in International Studies", 1972 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - "Thoughts on the Undergraduate Interdisciplinary Program, Center for International Studies, Cornell University" by Anthony J. La Vopa, September 4, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - International Studies Undergraduate Teaching Program, July 1971 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Proposal: Interdisciplinary Program in International Studies for Freshmen and Sophomores (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Composite Draft of Sub-Committee Proposal for a Possible Program in International Studies for Freshmen and Sophomores (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - "The Cornell Inter-Disciplinary Program in International Studies" (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - John W. Mellor's Statement on the Center of International Studies, November 7, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - A Proposal to Examine the Meaning of International Relations or the University Response to a Restructured World Environment, June 7, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Steven Muller's Statement on the Center of International Studies, December 28, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - "The University and World Affairs", 1960 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - "The College and University in International Affairs" (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - "The Ford Foundation in the 1960s," Statement of the Board of Trustees on Policies, Programs, and Operations, July 1962 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - "Summary of the Preliminary Recommendations of the CIS Evaluation Committee", February 28, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Douglas E. Ashford's Discussion of the Future of CIS, July 12, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Stephen Frick on the Committee on Undergraduate Programs in International Studies, October 19, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - "A Statement to the Division of International Training and Research, the Ford Foundation Concerning Renewal of Support for the Program of International Studies at Cornell University", June 10, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Response from Soviet Studies to Sander's Report, May 14, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - G. Levine's Comments on Undergraduate Teaching in International Studies, July 1, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - Outline for Luncheon to Initiate Planning Committee for Undergraduate Teaching Program in International Relations, September 10, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - Organization and Functions: Center for International Studies (Box 18, Folder 54)
  - "Proposed Undergraduate International Relations Major", September 12, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 55)
  - Assorted Excerpts From Correspondence and Interviews, 1964-1973 (Box 18, Folder 56)
  - "Undergraduate Program in International Studies," Description, June 17, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 57)
  - "The Planned Strengthening of International Studies at Cornell," 1968, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 58)
  - Assorted Correspondence About International Studies, 1970-1973 (Box 18, Folder 59)
  - Assorted Papers Concerning International Studies, 1960s and 1970s (Box 18, Folder 60)
- Series VII. Departmental Affairs
  - International Population Program
    - IPP Budget, Secretarial Support - Payroll, 1960s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Intl Population Progr: Organization and Set Up of IPP, 1960s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - International Population Program, 1961-1971 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - IPP Grants: Rockefeller, 1969-1975 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - IPP Budget-Account Numbers, 1970-1975 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - IPP Grants: Population Council, 1971-1974 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - IPP Report of Activities Used as Background for Ford Foundation Site Visit, May 23, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - IPP Proposals National Endowment of Arts ("Political Support of a Multi-media Exhibit on Population"), 1972 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "Proposal to the Ford Foundation from the International Population Program", December 1972 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - IPP Proposals: NIH, July 2, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - "Training in International Population Research", 1976 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - IPP Proposals: Population Council, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - International Population Program Papers, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - The Report and Recommendations of the Committee on New Directions in the Social Sciences, June 7, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Assorted Sociology Papers, March 1966-Spring 1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of the Study Committee for Sociology, November 1968 and February 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meetings of the Graduate Field of Public Policy, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Applications for Graduate Program in Public Policy and Administration, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Discussion on Cornell's Public Policy, May 1975 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Assorted Papers Concerning the Advancement of Asian Studies, 1972-1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - FALCON Proposal (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Papers About Development of Asian Studies Activities (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Various Papers on Latin American Studies, 1957-1977 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - "Request for Support for Administrative Expenses: Cornell University Latin American Programs", March 10, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - "A Proposal to Carnegie Corporation for the Establishment of a Program of Latin American Studies at Cornell University", January 30, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Notes on a Meeting Concerning Cornell's Latin America Program, April 17, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Assorted Information About Cornell's Foreign Programs, Especially Latin American, 1961-1968 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Draft of the Progress Report for the Latin American Year, March 1, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - "Draft of a Grant Request to the Xerox Foundation for the Establishment of the Allan R. Holmberg Andean Documentation Center in Cornell University", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - LAP Staff Correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Assorted Pages Concerning Cornell's Latin American Studies Program, 1967-1979 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Minutes for Inter-University Committee on Andean Studies Meeting at Penn State, December 12-13, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Assorted Papers on Andean Studies, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Project Grant Application for Latin American Studies, October 30, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Assorted Copies of Constitution and By-Laws of Northeast Consortium for Andean Studies, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence Between the Northeast Consortium for Andean Studies, July 1970-May 1972 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Latin American Studies at Cornell University Preliminary Statement, February 1971 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Andean Research Center, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - "Latin American Language and Area Center Request for 15 NDFL Fellowships", 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence Between the Northeast Consortium for Andean Studies, May 1972-January 1974 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Quechua Summer Course, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Cuzco University, May 1973 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - "A Plan of Operation for a Continuation of the Language and Area Center for Latin America at Cornell University", 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Latin America Today, Heritage of Conquest: A Conference at Cornell University; Brochure, April 3-5, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - "Narrative Description of Latin American Studies at Cornell University" (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - "Northeast Consortium for Andean Studies Constitution and By-Laws" (Draft) (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - "Latin American Studies in American Universities" (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - "Linguistic Research in Latin America: The Peruvian Andes" (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Proposal for Establishment of a Program of Latin American Studies at Cornell University (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - "Latin American Studies Report," by Allan R. Holmberg (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Cornell University Program on Science and Technology and Society, Publications, Spring 1974 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Application for Establishing a Center of European Studies, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - China Program and East Asia Center, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - South Asia, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Southeast Asia Program, 1965-1973 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Slavic Studies/Russian Literature, February 1966 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - "The Department of City and Regional Planning: Ten-Year Projection of Department Needs for International Programs", March 24, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Assorted Women's Studies Programs Papers, Including Courses, 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Assorted Women's Studies Program Papers, May 1973-October 1975 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence About the Appointment of Cynthia Frey to the Women's Studies Program, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - "Women's Studies Newsletter," No.1, September 1, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Alice Cook's Appointment to the Women's Studies Program, August 4, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Report of the Ad Hoc Committee for Review of the Women's Studies Program (and other related files), 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - South Asian Studies Papers and Correspondence About Hiring New Faculty, 1968-1967 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - South Asian Studies Presentations and Lectures, February 1975-September 1976 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Description of Cornell Southeast Asia Program (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Comp. Pol. Anal.--Proposal, January 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Mainly Focused Around Comparative Policy, August 1975-July 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Comparative Policy Correspondence and Papers, September 1975-November 1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Comp. Pol. Anal.--Proposal Renewal, January 1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Canadian Studies Proposals/Grants/Funding, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Assorted Sociology Studies and Correspondence, November-December 1980 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Applied Anthro Program: CU Studies in Culture and Applied Science, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - "South Asia Language and Area Center: Technical Report", 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - "Proposals for Continuation of Easy Asia Language and Area Center at Cornell University in 1968-1969" (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Asian Studies Administrative Papers, mid-1960s (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Latin American Program, December 1965 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - "Technical Report for 1964-1965 on the East Asia Language and Area Center at Cornell University" (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - "Technical Report for 1963-1964 on the East Asia Language and Area Center at Cornell University" (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - "Technical Report for 1962-1963 on the East Asia Language and Area Center at Cornell University" (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - "Technical Report for 1961-1962 on the East Asia Language and Area Center at Cornell University" (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - "Annual Technical on the Operation of the Corn ell East Asia Language and Area Center for the Year", 1960-1961 (Box 15, Folder 19)
- Series VIII. Proposals and Proposal Materials
  - Various Papers About Preparing a Research Project (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - CIS and South Asia Studies Correspondence, 1967-1976 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Application to the National Science Foundation for a Doctoral Dissertation by Satya Prakash Sharma, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Report on CIC Summer School in South Asian Studies, September 29, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cornell University Master's Thesis on Asia, August 1974 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Addresses of Those Involved with South Asian Studies, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Proposal to National Science Foundation from Cornell University for Interdisciplinary Program on Science, Technology, and Society, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - "Technology, Arms Development, and European Defense Research Proposal", 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Proposal Strengthening European Studies at Cornell University, a Program for 1970-1973, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Proposal to the National Science Foundation for Support of Research on an Empirical and Theoretical Investigation of the Participatory Economy, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - CIS Proposal to John S. Knight for Endowment for International Studies, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Proposal to Study "The Role of Multinational Corporations in the Western Hemisphere", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - CIS Contingency Proposal for Funding Interdisciplinary Courses on Undergraduate Level, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Proposal for a "Center for the Analysis of World Food Issues", 1976 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - "A Proposal for Establishment of a New Minor Field in the Graduate School: Political Economy and Public Policy (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - "Proposal to the Tinker Foundation for the Support of the 39th International Congress of Americanists in Connection with Symposia on "Problems and Possibilities of International Collaboration in Social Research," submitted by William F. White (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - A Proposal to the Agency for International Development Office of Science and Technology for Selected Project on Science and Technology Policy for Developing Nations, June 24, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Center for International Studies Assorted Proposals, November 27, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Application for Research Grant: "Social Structure and Change in Developing Areas", May 28, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Upper Volta Fertility Study Proposal", 1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Summary of Proposal for Research and Training: Water Management in the Humid Tropics", November 1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Forms for Major Giants in International Studies Received by Cornell University, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - National Research Program in Brazil Proposal, May 1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Proposal to the Office of Education for Support of an Inter-Disciplinary Program on Methods of Comparative Study of Developmental Change," By Professors of the ILR School, October 15, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Thomas Stephens' Proposal to the Program in International Agricultural Development, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Request for Proposal Agricultural Education Planning, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Paperwork for Proposals for Cornell Summer Research, June 23, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Cooperative Program in Graduate Education and Research, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Grant Proposals, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Grant Award Lists, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Proposal to the National Science Foundation for Support of Research on Social Structure and Change in Developing Areas, Submitted by Professors of the ILR School, early 1970s (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Proposal: Model Comprehensive Nutrition Program for Wonsiong County, Korea; Development and Production of Law Cost, High-Nutrition Food, by Michael J. McFadden (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Proposals-ILR to NIH, February 15, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - ILR Proposal to NSF, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Comparative Political Behavior Project, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Proposal for a Degree of Master of Professional Studies, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Proposal for a Degree of Master of Professional Studies (International Development), June-August 1972 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Proposal for a Degree of Master of Professional Studies (International Development), August 28, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Proposal for a Degree of Master of Professional Studies (International Development), December 29, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Proposal for a Degree of Master of Professional Studies, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Proposal for a Degree of Master of Professional Studies, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - The Evaluation of University Centers: A Proposed Role for the Committee on Academic Programs and Policy, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - ILR School: International Activities, A Program for the Next Ten Years, October 1965 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Proposal to National Science Foundation for Curriculum Innovation in the Area of Science, Technology, and Society, Draft by R. Bowers, February 3, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Proposal for Support Under the Agency for International Development, Institutional Grants Program, October 1972 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - "Proposal for Research and/or Related Activities Submitted to the US Commissioner of Education for Support Through Authorization of the Bureau of Research," 1960s, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "Organizational Change in Developing Nations: A Study of Organizational Dynamics in Developing Societies Focusing on Trade Unions in Africa," Research Period July 1966-August 1969, by William H. Friedland (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - E.Europe - Fisher, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Environ. GeneralE, 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - NICHHD Proposal Rejection, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - "Interdisciplinary Training Program in Applied Social Demography", 1974 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - "Application for Training Grant Continuation Report" and Related Papers, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Johnson Foundation Papers and Proposals, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Papers on Milton J. Esman's Proposal: "The Cornell Inter-disciplinary Program in International Studies", April 28, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Proposal: Interdisciplinary Program in International Studies for Freshman and Sophomores (Box 18, Folder 33)
- Series IX. Education Documents
  - National Defense of Education Act
    - Funding Patterns for International Studies - Foreign Language and Area Studies (NDEA), 1970s (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Concerning Proposals for Language Programs to be Funded by NDEA, 1964-1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Papers Concerning Meetings for and Discussion of NDEA VI, 1967-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Technical Report for 1967-1968 of the NDEA Language and Area Center for Latin American Studies", June 24, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Budget Information in Light of NDEA Title VI, 1968-1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Papers on the Consequences of Losing NDEA VI Funding, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "Technical Report for 1969-1970 of the NDEA Language and Area Center for Latin American Studies", June 19, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Memoranda Relaying News Concerning NDEA VI, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - NDEA Update, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - NDEA 1972 Campaign to Congress, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - "Invitation for Proposals for Assistance to Problem or Topic Oriented Programs in International Studies at the Graduate Level," NDEA Title VI, October 15, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - NDEA 1972 Strategy - General, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Assorted Papers Reacting to the Loss of Funding for NDEA Title VI, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - NDEA International Studies Programs at the Undergraduate level, Distribution of Federal Support, 1972-1976 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - NDEA International Studies Programs at the Graduate level, Distribution of Federal Support, 1972-1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Papers on Funding and NDEA Title VI, 1972-1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - "The Disabling Consequences of the Termination of NDEA Title VI," by Richard D. Lambert, February 13, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Papers on the Decline of the NDEA and its Funding, February 1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - "Technical Report for 1972-1973 of the NDEA Language and Area Center for Latin American Studies", July 1973 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Papers on NDEA and the ACE International Education Project, October 18, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - NDEA VI - 1973 Fellowship Support, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - NDEA Crisis Papers, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Papers Discussing NEDA VI, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - NDEA Centers for International and Language and Area Studies Distribution of Federal Support, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - NDEA Centers for International and Language and Area Studies Distribution of Federal Support, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Papers on Loss of NDEA Title VI, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - January 8th NDEA New York Meeting, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Responses to Loss of NDEA Title VI, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Latin American Program NDEA Center Application, March 8, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Application for 1978-1979 NDEA Title VI Fellowship, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - NDEA Title VI Fellowship Competition, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - "Funding Patterns for International Studies - Background on Funding," Concerning NDEA VI (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - NDEA Organization of 1970 Campaign (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - NDEA 1970 Correspondence to Congress (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - NDEA 1970 Replies from Congress (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - NDEA 1970 Gen Followup to Campaign (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Federal Action Concerning NDEA VI, 1970, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - NDEA Support, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - NDEA VI Fellowships, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - NDEA-1971 Campaign Correspondence and Response (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Proposal for the Establishment of the Overseas Educational Service, Carnegie Corporation of New York, March 21, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Education and World Affairs Documents, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Papers About the Regional Conference for the International Education Act, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Information for Institute of International Education About Cornell Programs Abroad, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Education and World Affairs Correspondence and Studies, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Papers Concerning Education and World Affairs, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Education and World Affairs Meeting Minutes and Documents, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Papers Concerning the International Education Act, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)